

CONTACT

- ♥ The Colony TX US
- thiyagarajan.angappan@gmail.com
- 1-210-862-6727
- % https://thiyagarajan-angappan.github.io/
- nttps://github.com/ thiyagarajan-angappan
- https://www.linkedin.com/ in/ thiyagarajan-
- https://twitter.com/ UndefObject

EDUCATION

3.72

Bachelor of Engineering, Anna University 2001 - 2005

SKILLS

Frontend Development

JavaScript ReactJS Redux HTML5/CSS3

Backend Development

Java RESTful Services Hibernate MSSQL

Build Gradle Maven Ant

CI/CD

Github Gitlab CirclCI

Methodologies

Agile Test Driven Development

VSCode IntelliJ Eclipse

Tools

Postman SOAP UI

THIYAGARAJAN ANGAPPAN

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

SUMMARY

Full stack engineer aimed at achieving the best solutions in the world of business problems. With over 15 years of experience in design and development of Web Applications, a **curious mind** towards researching and learning emerging technologies, I invest in **self growth** and guide others to reach their best

EXPERIENCE

TECHNICAL ARCHITECT

HCL America Inc | https://www.hcltech.com/geo-presence/united-states | Jul 2018 - Present

Leading 3 teams, responsible for plan, design of technical architecture and implementation of new life insurance product. Understand problem statements and business needs of the customer and design the best solutions

- Trained recently on-boarded remote developers and completed a trouble free release of introducing a new product to public in an older codebase
- Created a web portal aimed at maintaining and monitoring vendor services.
- Successfully prototyped the **implementation of ELK stack** for vendor services
- Designed enhanced SOAP UI portal for statistics and validation
- Averted missing deadline by fixing a major bug in dozer mapping during websphere migration effort

SENIOR CONSULTANT

Openlink Financial LLC | https://openlink.com/ | Aug 2015 - Jun 2018 (2 years 10 months)

Engaged and discussed with traders to understand their day to day activities, identified potential tasks to automate, reduced manual intervention and increased productivity

- Designed and programmed master data compatible with various ways of report generation
- Improved Quarterly report time taken to complete by 70 to 80 percent
- Handled bundling, delivery and installation of completed software in customer systems

ASSISTANT CONSULTANT

TATA Consultancy Service Ltd | https://www.tcs.com/ | Nov 2006 - Aug 2015 (8 years 9 months)

Lead a team of 2 senior programmers onsite, 2 in mexico and 10 in India, translated business needs to technical tasks and helped replace mainframe screens to web based applications

- Mentored / trained team members in technologies used and processes followed in project delivery
- Improved time to market by 30% in the implementation of UX changes
- Pioneered the design and implementation of esign integration for insurance products

VOLUNTEER

FRONTEND ENGINEER

ClimateMind | https://climatemind.org/ | Jun 2020 - Oct 2020 (4 months)

Conerned and alarmed about climate change, volunteered to create a platform, a conversation starter to help those who are undecided about climate change and its dreadful impacts

Created Materail UI base for React App

AWARDS

- Cyberark Certified Trustee | Sep 2019 | CyberArk
- Distinguished Achiever | Sep 2019 | HCL America Inc
- Technical Excellence | Jun 2013 | TATA Consultancy Services Ltd

LANGUAGES

- Tamil English

INTERESTS

- Web Development / Algorithms Leetcode Hackerrank Frontend Masters overreacted.io
 - Photography
 - Portraiture Fashion Landscape
- Running
- 5k Morning runs Trail runs

REFERENCES



Thiyagarajan (Mr T) is a skillful Java developer when we worked together at OpenLink Financial as consultants for one of the most well-known energy trading and risk management ETRM company. In addition to his technical professionalism, his soft people skills has helped in situations wherein a technical person must be able to relate to non-technical ones in order to comprehend the described issue. T is a fast learner and able to translate business jargons into technical solutions.

— Mimi Nguyen, Computer Software Professional